<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on Project F - FPGA Development</title>
    <link>https://projectf.io/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on Project F - FPGA Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>©2020 Will Green, Project F</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://projectf.io/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building iCE40 FPGA Toolchain on Linux</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/building-ice40-fpga-toolchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/building-ice40-fpga-toolchain/</guid>
      <description>Since I tested FPGA development tools on Ubuntu 20.04, there have been requests for more posts on FPGA tooling. In this post, I provide a quick guide to building an open-source FPGA toolchain for iCE40 boards, such as iCEBreaker. I plan to follow this up with an ECP5 version later.
This guide is designed for Ubuntu or Pop!_OS 20.04, but should be straightforward to adjust to your own distro. These instructions will work on Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL), but there&amp;rsquo;s no USB support in WSL, so you can&amp;rsquo;t program boards under WSL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA Tooling on Ubuntu 20.04</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-dev-ubuntu-20.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-dev-ubuntu-20.04/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I test common FPGA tools for compatibility with Ubuntu 20.04 (AKA Focal Fossa), and my regular desktop OS: Pop!_OS 20.04. These tests are in no way exhaustive: I have tried using the applications as I usually do to exercise the main functionality. I have also included instructions for building the tools from source when available. This is my final planned update for this post (July 2020).
 Tested: IceStorm Tools, nextpnr, nMigen, Verilator, Vivado, Yosys Incomplete: Quartus  Updated 2020-07-30.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>