<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maths on Project F - FPGA Development</title>
    <link>https://projectf.io/tags/maths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maths on Project F - FPGA Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>©2021 Will Green, Project F</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://projectf.io/tags/maths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Square Root in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/square-root-in-verilog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/square-root-in-verilog/</guid>
      <description>The square root is useful in many circumstances, including statistics, graphics, and signal processing. In this FPGA recipe, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at a straightforward digit-by-digit square root algorithm for integer and fixed-point numbers. There are lower-latency methods, but this one is simple, using only subtraction and bit shifts. You might also be interested in Division in Verilog.
Updated 2021-01-04. Feedback to @WillFlux is most welcome.
Getting Radical The square root of a number is a second number that multiplied by itself produces the first number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Division in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/division-in-verilog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/division-in-verilog/</guid>
      <description>Division is a fundamental arithmetic operation; one we take for granted in most contexts. FPGAs are different; Verilog can&amp;rsquo;t synthesize division: we need to do it ourselves. In this FPGA recipe, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at a straightforward division algorithm for positive integers and fixed-point numbers. For integers, this method takes one cycle per bit: 32 cycles for 32-bit numbers. You might also be interested in Square Root in Verilog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed Point Numbers in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/fixed-point-numbers-in-verilog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fixed-point-numbers-in-verilog/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need more precision than integers can provide, but floating-point computation is not trivial (try reading IEEE 754). You could use a library or IP block, but simple fixed point maths can often get the job done with little effort. Furthermore, most FPGAs have dedicated DSP blocks that make multiplication and addition of integers fast; we can take advantage of that with a fixed-point approach.
This post is part of a series of handy recipes to solve common FPGA development problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>