<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>verilator on Project F</title><link>https://projectf.io/tags/verilator/</link><description>Recent content in verilator on Project F</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://projectf.io/tags/verilator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mandelbrot in Verilog</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/mandelbrot-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/mandelbrot-verilog/</guid><description>This FPGA demo uses fixed-point multiplication and a small framebuffer to render the Mandelbrot set. You can navigate around the complex plane using buttons on your dev board.
The demo doesn&amp;rsquo;t run at 60 FPS because it only considers one pixel at a time. I may extend the design in future: it currently uses just 9 of the 740 DSPs on the Nexys Video!
Share your thoughts with @WillFlux on Mastodon or Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Rasterbars</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/rasterbars/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/rasterbars/</guid><description>This FPGA demo effect renders four animated rasterbars. I created this effect with benjamin.computer for All You Need, a Chapterhouse prod released at Revision 2022.
For an introduction to rasterbars and other simple graphics effects, check out Racing the Beam.
The design was originally for a custom Artix-7 dev board, but this version runs on the Digilent Arty A7 or as a Verilator/SDL simulation on your computer.
Share your thoughts with @WillFlux on Mastodon or Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Sine Scroller</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/sinescroll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/sinescroll/</guid><description>This FPGA demo effect renders a horizontally scrolling message along a sine wave. I created this effect with benjamin.computer for All You Need, a Chapterhouse prod released at Revision 2022.
The design was originally for a custom Artix-7 dev board, but this version runs on the Digilent Arty A7 or as a Verilator/SDL simulation on your computer.
Share your thoughts with @WillFlux on Mastodon or Twitter. If you like what I do, sponsor me.</description></item><item><title>Castle Drawing</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/castle-drawing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/castle-drawing/</guid><description>In this FPGA demo, we use multiple shapes (rectangles, triangles, circles) to render a simple picture of a castle. We don&amp;rsquo;t use any software or CPU, just shape rasterization and finite state machines. This Verilog design runs on the Digilent Arty A7 or as a Verilator/SDL simulation on your computer.
Share your thoughts with @WillFlux on Mastodon or Twitter. If you like what I do, sponsor me. 🙏
Building the Demo Find the Verilog source and build instructions in the projf-explore git repo:</description></item><item><title>Racing the Beam</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/racing-the-beam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/racing-the-beam/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. Last time, we got an introduction to FPGA graphics; let&amp;rsquo;s put our new graphical skills to work with some simple demo effects. I hope these examples inspire you to create your own effects and improve your hardware design skills.
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn how screens work, play Pong, create starfields and sprites, paint Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s David, draw lines and triangles, and animate characters and shapes.</description></item><item><title>Animated Shapes</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/animated-shapes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/animated-shapes/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. In the final part of our introductory graphics series, we&amp;rsquo;re looking at animation. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen animation with hardware sprites, but double buffering gives us maximum creative freedom with fast, tear-free motion. We&amp;rsquo;ll be making extensive use of our designs from 2D Shapes, so have a look back at that post if you need a refresher on drawing shapes.
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs.</description></item><item><title>Verilog Simulation with Verilator and SDL</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/verilog-sim-verilator-sdl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/verilog-sim-verilator-sdl/</guid><description>It can be challenging to test your FPGA or ASIC graphics designs. You can perform low-level behavioural simulations and examine waveforms, but you also need to verify how the video output will appear on the screen.
By combining Verilator and SDL, you can build Verilog simulations that let you see your design on your computer. The thought of creating a graphical simulation can be intimidating, but it&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly simple: you&amp;rsquo;ll have your first simulation running in under an hour.</description></item><item><title>2D Shapes</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-shapes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-shapes/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. In 2D Shapes, we build on what we learned from Lines and Triangles in two ways: drawing new shapes and learning to colour them in. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with rectangles and filled triangles before moving on to circles. These basic shapes make it possible to create a wide variety of graphics and user interfaces.
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs.</description></item><item><title>Lines and Triangles</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/lines-and-triangles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/lines-and-triangles/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. It&amp;rsquo;s time to turn our attention to drawing. Most modern computer graphics come down to drawing triangles and colouring them in. So, it seems fitting to begin our drawing tour with triangles and the straight lines that form them. This post will implement Bresenham&amp;rsquo;s line algorithm in Verilog and create lines, triangles, and even a cube (our first sort-of 3D).
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs.</description></item><item><title>Verilog Lint with Verilator</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/verilog-lint-with-verilator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/verilog-lint-with-verilator/</guid><description>Hardware design can be unforgiving, so it pays to use any advantage you can get. Verilator is a Verilog simulator and C++ compiler that also supports linting: statically analysing your designs for issues. Not only can Verilator spot problems your synthesis tool might overlook, but it also runs quickly. Verilator is also great for graphics simulation with SDL.
Share your thoughts with @WillFlux on Mastodon or Twitter. If you like what I do, sponsor me.</description></item><item><title>iCE40 FPGA Toolchain on Linux</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/building-ice40-fpga-toolchain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/building-ice40-fpga-toolchain/</guid><description>Since I tested FPGA development tools on Ubuntu 20.04, there have been requests for more posts on FPGA tooling. In this post, I provide a quick guide to building an open-source FPGA toolchain for iCE40 boards, such as iCEBreaker. I plan to cover ECP5 FPGAs in a future version.
This guide is designed for Ubuntu or Pop!_OS 20.04, but should be straightforward to adjust to your own distro. These instructions will work on Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL), but there&amp;rsquo;s no USB support in WSL, so you can&amp;rsquo;t program boards under WSL.</description></item><item><title>Framebuffers</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/framebuffers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/framebuffers/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. In the previous part, we worked with sprites, but another approach is needed as graphics become more complex. Instead of drawing directly to the screen, we draw to a bitmap, which is read out to the screen. This post provides an introduction to framebuffers and how to scale them up. We&amp;rsquo;ll also learn how to fizzlefade graphics Wolfenstein 3D style.
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Sprites</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/hardware-sprites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/hardware-sprites/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. In the previous part, we updated our display signals and learnt about colour palettes. This part shows you how to create fast, colourful graphics with minimal logic. Hardware sprites maintain much of the simplicity of our Pong design while offering greater creative freedom.
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn how screens work, play Pong, create starfields and sprites, paint Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s David, draw lines and triangles, and animate characters and shapes.</description></item><item><title>FPGA Pong</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-pong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-pong/</guid><description>Welcome back to Exploring FPGA Graphics. Last time, we raced the beam; this time, we&amp;rsquo;ll recreate the arcade classic, Pong and play against our FPGA.
In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn how screens work, play Pong, create starfields and sprites, paint Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s David, draw lines and triangles, and animate characters and shapes. New to the series?</description></item><item><title>Beginning FPGA Graphics</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-graphics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-graphics/</guid><description>Welcome to Exploring FPGA Graphics. In this series, we learn about graphics at the hardware level and get a feel for the power of FPGAs. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn how screens work, play Pong, create starfields and sprites, paint Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s David, draw lines and triangles, and animate characters and shapes. Along the way, you&amp;rsquo;ll experience a range of designs and techniques, from memory and finite state machines to crossing clock domains and translating C algorithms into Verilog.</description></item><item><title>FPGA Tooling on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-dev-ubuntu-20.04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-dev-ubuntu-20.04/</guid><description>In this post, I test common FPGA tools for compatibility with Ubuntu 20.04 (AKA Focal Fossa), and my regular desktop OS: Pop!_OS 20.04. These tests are in no way exhaustive: I have tried using the applications as I usually do to exercise the main functionality. I have also included instructions for building the tools from source when available. This is my final update for this post (July 2020).
Tested: IceStorm Tools, nextpnr, nMigen, Verilator, Vivado, Yosys Incomplete: Quartus Share your thoughts with @WillFlux on Mastodon or Twitter.</description></item></channel></rss>