<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Isle on Project F</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/isle/</link><description>Recent content in Isle on Project F</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/isle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Isle Design</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle-design/</guid><description>Isle is a computer&amp;hellip; (common intro). In this post I discuss the Isle design and why I made these choices. I aimed to keep everything as simple as possible, while supporting a wide-range of applications.
Following this post will be monthly Isle updates&amp;hellip;
CPU Simple 32-bit RISC-V processor runs system and controls other hardware. Performance is broadly comparable with a 486 or Motorola 68040, thought our CPU doesn&amp;rsquo;t have hardware floating point.</description></item><item><title>Why Build a Computer?</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle-why/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle-why/</guid><description>Isle is a computer&amp;hellip; (common intro). Why I&amp;rsquo;m building a computer and why you might want to join me.
I love islands. A small island is a world within a world; it fits in the mind yet feels liberating and alive with possibilities. Most of us can&amp;rsquo;t or don&amp;rsquo;t want to live on a small island. However, a small island can provide a temporary refuge from the wider world, a place to play, experiment, and restore perspective.</description></item><item><title>Isle Quick Start</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle-quick-start/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle-quick-start/</guid><description>Isle is a computer&amp;hellip; (common intro). In this post I show you how to get started with Isle in software and hardware.
Separate quick start pages for each board / simulator?
Stay tuned for more user guides soon (The Book of the Isles).
More About Isle Isle FPGA Computer - Introducing the Isle computer Isle Design - The Isle design and how I decided on it Why Build a Computer?</description></item><item><title>Isle FPGA Computer</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/isle/</guid><description>Be not afeard; the isle is full of noises, Sounds, and sweet airs, that give delight and hurt not.
Shakespeare, The Tempest
I&amp;rsquo;m building an FPGA computer called Isle. In this post, I will introduce Isle and hopefully inspire you to come on a journey with me.
Isle is a simple, modern computer. Simple in that one person can understand the whole thing: hardware and software. Modern in that it learns from the best of computers past, works with modern development tools, file formats, and Unicode.</description></item></channel></rss>