<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Project F</title>
    <link>https://projectf.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Project F</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>©2020 Will Green, Project F</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://projectf.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed Point Numbers in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/fixed-point-numbers-in-verilog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fixed-point-numbers-in-verilog/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need more precision than integers can provide, but floating-point computation is not trivial (try reading IEEE 754). You could use a library or IP block, but simple fixed point maths can often get the job done with little effort. Furthermore, most FPGAs have dedicated DSP blocks that make multiplication and addition of integers fast; we can take advantage of that with a fixed-point approach.
This post is part of a series of handy recipes to solve common FPGA development problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring FPGA Graphics</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-graphics/</guid>
      <description>In all beginnings dwells a magic force
Herman Hesse, The Glass Bead Game, 1943
 Welcome to Exploring FPGA Graphics with Project F. In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll be experimenting with FPGA graphics of all kinds, from a static square, through Pong and the Mandelbrot set, to bitmaps, text scrollers, and even 3D modelling. There&amp;rsquo;s no microcontroller in any of these designs: they&amp;rsquo;re simple logic described in SystemVerilog.
This post is a quick introduction to generating graphics with FPGAs: you&amp;rsquo;ll learn about display signals and simple colour graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Arty - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/hello-arty-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/hello-arty-2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to our three-part FPGA tutorial with SystemVerilog and the Digilent Arty A7. In part two, we&amp;rsquo;re going to learn about clocks and counting. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover maintaining state with flip-flops, timing things with clock dividers, creating our first Verilog module, and controlling LEDs with pulse width modulation. You might be surprised how far counting takes you: by the end of this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;ll be creating RGB lighting effects worthy of a cheesy gaming PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Arty - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/hello-arty-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/hello-arty-1/</guid>
      <description>People who are really serious about software should make their own hardware.
Alan Kay, Creative Think seminar, 1982
 This three-part tutorial provides a quick introduction to FPGA development with SystemVerilog and the Digilent Arty A7 board. No prior experience of FPGA development is required, but basic knowledge of programming concepts is assumed. If you can write a simple program in Arduino, Python, or JavaScript, then you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have any trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initialize Memory in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/initialize-memory-in-verilog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/initialize-memory-in-verilog/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common for a simulation or firmware to need data loading into a memory array, ram, or rom. Fortunately, Verilog provides the $readmemh and $readmemb functions for this very purpose. Unfortunately, there is a dearth of good Verilog documentation online, so using them can be harder than it should be. This article explains the syntax and provides plenty of examples, including how to do this in Xilinx Vivado.
This post is part of a series of handy recipes to solve common FPGA development problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA Tooling on Ubuntu 20.04</title>
      <link>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-dev-ubuntu-20.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://projectf.io/posts/fpga-dev-ubuntu-20.04/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I test common FPGA tools for compatibility with Ubuntu 20.04 (AKA Focal Fossa), and my regular desktop OS: Pop!_OS 20.04. These tests are in no way exhaustive: I have tried using the applications as I usually do to exercise the main functionality. For me, the biggest gain in moving to 20.04 has been the responsiveness of the desktop.
 Tested: IceStorm Tools, nextpnr, nMigen, Verilator, Vivado, Yosys In Progress: Quartus  Last updated 2020-06-05 follow WillFlux for future updates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>